<topic xmlns="" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="https://helpserver.labs.jb.gg/help/topic.v2.xsd"
       xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" id="A_Ktor_Application" title="A Ktor Application">
    <p>Ktor can be used to create a variety of server and <a href="clients_index.md">client-side</a> applications.
        Whether we want to create a website that serves static and dynamic pages, an HTTP endpoint, a RESTful system, or
        even microservices, Ktor makes it all possible.
    </p>
    <p>In this section, we're going to cover the basics of what a Ktor Server Application is and how the pieces all fit
        together.
    </p>
    <chapter id="hello-world" title="The Simplest Ktor Application">
        <p>One of Ktor's goals is to remain as simple as possible and to avoid any kind of <i>magic</i>. The equivalent
            to a <i>Hello World</i> application in Ktor would be:
        </p>
        <code style="block"
              lang="kotlin"
              src="snippets/_misc/HelloWorld.kt"
              include-symbol="main">
        </code>
        <p>
            We start by <a href="create_server.xml">creating a server</a>, in this case using Netty as an <a href="Engines.md">Engine</a>, and setting the port to 8000. After this, we define a route to respond to requests made to <path>/</path> with a simple <emphasis>Hello, world!</emphasis> text. Finally, we start the server.
        </p>
    </chapter>



    <chapter title="Next Steps" id="next">
        <p>
            In the next chapters, we'll take a look at the main concepts of creating a Ktor application -
            from configuring a server to using features, which is core to all Ktor applications:
        </p>

        <list>
            <li>
                <p>
                    <a href="create_server.xml">Choose a way to create a server</a><br/>
                    You can quickly configure a server using the <code>embeddedServer</code> function, or you can use <code>EngineMain</code> to have additional configuration possibilities.
                </p>
            </li>
            <li>
                <p>
                    <a href="Engines.md">Choose an engine</a><br/>
                    Configuring a server requires choosing an engine, such as Netty, Jetty, Tomcat, and so on.
                </p>
            </li>
            <li>
                <p>
                    <a href="Configurations.xml">Configure a server</a><br/>
                    Learn how to configure various server parameters (such as a host address and port, modules to load, etc.), read the configuration in code, and use environment variables.
                </p>
            </li>
            <li>
                <p>
                    <a href="Features.md">Add functionality with Features</a><br/>
                    Get acquainted with features that provide common functionality, for example, serialization and content encoding, compression, headers, cookie support, etc.
                </p>
            </li>
            <li>
                <p>
                    <a href="Routing_in_Ktor.md">Handle requests with Routing</a><br/>
                    Learn how to handle incoming requests made to different URLs using routing.
                </p>
            </li>
            <li>
                <p>
                    <a href="Modules.md">Divide your application into Modules</a><br/>
                     Use modules to divide your application into logical parts, each of which can house any functionality.
                </p>
            </li>
            <li>
                <p>
                    <a href="Structuring_Applications.md">Structure your application</a><br/>
                    Learn how to structure your application to keep it maintainable as the application grows.
                </p>
            </li>
        </list>
    </chapter>



<!--    <chapter id="the-request-and-response-pipeline" title="The Request and Response Pipeline">
        <p>The request and response flow for a Ktor application is represented by the following diagram:</p>
        <p>
            <img src="request-response-pipeline.svg" alt="Request and response pipeline"/>
        </p>
        <p>When a request comes in, it is processed by the routing mechanism, which redirects it to the route handler.
            This route handle consists of our application logic which could be anything from responding with a simple
            text (like the example above), to processing the input, storing it in a database, etc. Finally, once
            everything is done, the handler should respond to the request.
        </p>
        <p>In the next section we'll look <a href="Features.md">Features</a> which is core to all Ktor applications, and
            provides much of the functionality, including routing!
        </p>
    </chapter>-->
</topic>