<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE topic SYSTEM "https://resources.jetbrains.com/stardust/html-entities.dtd">

<topic xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="https://resources.jetbrains.com/stardust/topic.v2.xsd"
       xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
       title="Create a Server"
       id="create_server" auxiliary-id="start_server">

    <p>
        To run a Ktor server application, you need to create a server first.
        Server configuration can include different settings:
        a server <a href="Engines.md">engine</a> (such as Netty, Jetty, etc.),
        various engine-specific options, host and port values, and so on.
        There are two main approaches in Ktor for creating and running a server:
    </p>

    <list>
        <li>
            <p>
                The <a anchor="embedded-server">embeddedServer</a> function is a simple way to configure server parameters in code and quickly run an application.
            </p>
        </li>
        <li>
            <p>
                <a anchor="engine-main">EngineMain</a> provides more flexibility to configure a server. You can specify server parameters in an <path>application.conf</path> file and change a configuration without recompiling your application. Moreover, you can run your application from a command line and override the required server parameters by passing corresponding command-line arguments.
            </p>
        </li>
    </list>


    <chapter title="embeddedServer" id="embedded-server">
        <p>
            The <code>embeddedServer</code> function is a simple way to configure server parameters in code and quickly run an application.
            In the code snippet below, it accepts an <a href="Engines.md">engine</a> and port as parameters to start a server.
            In the example below, we run a server with the <code>Netty</code> engine and listen on the <code>8000</code> port:
        </p>
        <code style="block"
              lang="kotlin"
              src="snippets/_misc/HelloWorld.kt">
        </code>
    </chapter>

    <chapter title="EngineMain" id="engine-main">
        <p>
            <code>EngineMain</code> starts a server with the selected engine and loads the <a href="Modules.md">application module</a> specified in the external <a href="Configurations.xml" anchor="hocon-file">application.conf</a> file. Besides modules to load, this file can include various server parameters (the <code>8080</code> port in the example below).
        </p>

        <tabs>
            <tab title="Application.kt">
                <code style="block"
                      lang="kotlin"
                      src="snippets/_misc/HelloWorldEngineMain.kt">
                </code>
            </tab>
            <tab title="application.conf">
                <code style="block"
                      src="snippets/_misc/HelloWorldEngineMain.conf">
                </code>
            </tab>
        </tabs>
    </chapter>


</topic>